Yesterday they were businessmen. Today they're
cowboys. Tomorrow they'll be walking funny.
City Slickers is a comedy, western film directed by Ron Underwood.
Three New York businessmen decide to take a "Wild West" vacation that turns
out not to be the relaxing vacation they had envisioned.
Mitch Robbins, played by Billy Crystal.
Phil Berquist, played by Daniel Stern.
Ed Furillo, played by Bruno Kirby.
Barbara Robbins, played by Patricia Wettig.
Bonnie Rayburn, played by Helen Slater.
Holly Robbins, played by Lindsay Crystal.
City Slickers is a 1991 American Western comedy film directed by Ron Underwood and starring Billy Crystal, Daniel Stern, Bruno Kirby and Jack
Palance, with supporting roles by Patricia Wettig, Helen Slater, Noble Willingham and Jake Gyllenhaal making his acting debut.
The film's screenplay was written by Lowell Ganz and Babaloo Mandel, and it was
shot in New York City, New Mexico, Durango, Colorado, and Spain.
City Slickers was released by Columbia Pictures on June 7, 1991.
The film received positive reviews from critics and grossed
$179 million against a $26 million budget.
For his performance, Palance won the Academy Award for Best Supporting Actor.
A sequel titled The Legend of Curly's Gold was released in 1994 with the same cast, with
the exception of Kirby, who was replaced by Jon Lovitz in a different role.
The film explores themes of stetson, vacation, cattle
drive, prairie, fish out of water.
The tone is lighthearted.